Sammy Robinson

Full Stack Developer

Prockton, MA 02301-3253

27 Mar 1990

Sammy.robinson777@gmail.com

PROFILE

I bring over ten years of experience as a full-stack engineer in web and mobile app development. My proficiency spans the entire development cycle, with a specific focus on front-end development using modern JavaScript libraries and frameworks. I'm recognized as an expert in JavaScript and Shopify. My passion for continuous learning, adaptability as a team player, and innovative problem-solving skills drive my work.

SKILLS

Frontend

Vue, Angular, React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Tailwind

Content Management System

Shopify, Hydrogen, Polaris, Liquid

Database Management Systems

MongoDB, MySQL, Redis

Backend

Node.js, Express, PHP, Laravel, GraphQL

Version Control Tools

Git(Github, Gitlab), SVN

DevOps

AWS(Lambda, API Gateway, Elasticsearch, S3, EC2), Firebase, Docker, Kubernetes, Testing tools (Cypress, Mocha, Jest, Enzyme)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aug 2021 – Aug 2023 Bethlehem, United States PieSoft, Senior Full Stack Engineer

- I contributed to a marketing platform project, employing a technology stack that included React, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Node, Java, Spring, and Laravel.
- I successfully set up AWS API Gateway to host the Laravel API using AWS Lambda functions.
- Additionally, I created Elasticsearch queries to ensure fast and precise search functionality and designed scalable RDS instances for relational databases.
- I also played a role in mentoring junior developers.

Jul 2018 – Jul 2021 NYC, United States

sophilabs, Full Stack Engineer

- Developed and customized e-commerce websites using technologies like React, Shopify, Hydrogen, Polaris, Liquid, GTM, Google Analytics 4.0, Google Ads, MySQL, and Google Map API.
- I have expertise in crafting visually appealing and interactive Shopify stores using modern JavaScript frameworks and Shopify's design systems.
- I've optimized performance with serverside rendering, seamlessly integrated the Polaris design system, and customized themes with React and Vue.js while leveraging Shopify's Hydrogen framework and Liquid templating language

Apr 2013 – Jun 2017 Sao Paulo, Brazil

mark2market, Software Developer

 Built website using Laravel, utilizing MySQL for the database, and a RESTful API for the backend.

Oct 2011 – Apr 2013

Freelancer, Software Developer

EDUCATION

Apr 2007 — Sep 2011 Rebouças, Curitiba, Brazil

Bachelor of Computer Science,

Federal Technological University of Paraná